

KEVIN MICHAEL SCHOTT

Freelance Web & Mobile App Developer

Address: Mühlenstraße 19, 39104 Magdeburg

Tel.: 0391 5054 8231 Email: <u>kevin@kms695.de</u> Website: <u>https://kms695.de</u>

ABOUT ME

Hey there, I am Kevin. Meanwhile I work for more than 8 years in IT. During my master's program of computer science I founded a successful internet startup and later decided to go on a freelance journey. My work is agile and remote by nature. I offer web & mobile app development with modern frameworks as well as IT consulting.

SKILLS

Frontend Development

- Vue, Svelte, Alpine.js
- HTML, CSS, Sass, Tailwind, WindiCSS

Blockchain / Web 3.0

• Solidity, web3.js, ethers.js, truffle, Subgraph

Backend Development

- Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript
- Python, C/C++
- GCloud / Firebase

Mobile App Development

React Native, Flutter, Capacitor

Other

- macOS, Linux
- REST, GraphQL

New Work

- Remote, agile, asynchronous
- Reliable, friendly, fast communicator

HOW I WORK ON A DAILY BASIS

Currently I work with Svelte, GraphQL, Sass, Tailwind, Firebase and macOS on a daily basis (fully remote). The other listed technologies are rather used on a monthly basis. I am open and happy to learn technologies and also very fast at it.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Work (as kms695 since 2022)

- Frontend Development for <u>rain</u> (Open Source Projects)
- Frontend Development for Next Nature based in Amsterdam
- Frontend Development for <u>tvcharts</u> (Open Source Project)

CIO & Founder (My own startup metab from 2019 - 2022)

- A startup I founded myself primarily working in the social media industry and developing apps for influencers
- Notable works are the mobile & web apps sellby and myylink
- These apps allow influencers to collect donations via small websites (Stripe)

Research Assistant / Software Engineering (OvGU Magdeburg from 2017 - 2019)

- During my studies I worked on <u>several research projects</u> and wrote scripts and plugins for IDEs like IntelliJ IDEA
- I wrote a python tool that collects and analyzes GitHub projects for common bugs that are registered in an Open Source database

Software Developer & Software Tester (Eudemonia Solutions AG from 2014 - 2017)

- At the beginning of my bachelor studies, I developed and tested enterprise software for the Volksbank in Germany at <u>this company</u>
- We primarily worked with Java EE, Vaadin, Spring und IBM DB2

EDUCATION

Otto-von-Guericke-Universität Magdeburg M. Sc. Computer Science

2018 - 2021

B. Sc. Computer Science

2014 - 2018

Oberstufenzentrum Wittenberge (Prignitz) Abitur

2011 - 2014

Sekundarschule Seehausen (Altmark) Secondary School

2005 - 2011

Grundschule Groß Garz (Zehrental) Primary School

2001 - 2005

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Linguistic proficiency German (native speaker)

English (business fluent)

Driver's license Class B (allowed to drive cars)

Interests Politics, journalism, sport / fitness,

pop culture, movies, manga